I'm Tomoe Mami.
I'm a third-year at your school,
Mitakihara Junior High.
And I'm a magical girl who formed a contract with Kyubey.
Another weird dream...
Good morning, Madoka!
I'll never forget the promises we exchanged
I still see it when I close my eyes
I'll move forward as I cast off
this darkness engulfing me
How long will it be before
I see that lost future again?
I'll walk upon this Earth,
and pierce this shadowy veil of unease,
as many times as necessary
The clock that's endlessly ticked away
now tells of the beginning
Let's open the once-closed door,
with these unwavering feelings
My heart started racing once again to paint the future
Even if I get stuck in a maze,
the beautiful blue sky will always be waiting for me
So I won't be afraid
No matter what happens next, I won't give in
I think that'd be really nice
Episode 2
Madoka, I heard you came home late last night.
An upperclassman from school
invited me to her house.
I'm not going to be an annoying mom
and impose a curfew and stuff,
but make sure you call home before dinner.
I'm sorry.
I guess no one else can see him.
What a beautiful room!
Wow...
I live alone, so make yourselves at home.
Though I admit you've caught me unprepared.
Mami, this is delicious!
It really is!
Thank you.
Since you've been chosen by Kyubey,
that means you two are now involved in this.
I think we should get everyone on the same page.
You bet!
Ask us anything at all.
Sayaka, you have that backwards.
Wow, that's pretty!
This is a Soul Gem.
When Kyubey forms a contract with a girl, a Soul Gem is born.
This is what identifies us as magical girls
and acts as the source of our power.
Contract, you said?
I can grant each of you one wish.
Wait, really?
What kind of wish?
Anything you want.
I can fulfill any miracle you wish for.
So it could be gold, silver,
priceless treasures, immortality...
Maybe even a feast fit for a Chinese emperor!
I'm not too sure about that last one...
In exchange for that wish,
a Soul Gem is produced.
Those who receive one are given the responsibility of fighting witches.
Witches?
Hey, Mom.
Hm?
What if... What if someone offered to grant you any wish you wanted with magic...
What would you—
I'd get rid of a board member or two.
The president is also getting a bit too old for this,
so maybe I would wish for him to retire...
But he hasn't even named a successor yet...
What if you became president then, Mom?
I didn't think about that.
I'll have to work things out
with the Sales Department first.
Planning and Administration
are already my puppets.
The only problem left
is the baldy in Accounting.
I'll just pull off his toupée.
Mom, you look scary.
What's a witch?
Are they different from magical girls?
If magical girls are born from wishes,
then witches are born from curses.
Magical girls spread hope,
whereas witches spread despair.
And to make matters worse,
they can't be seen by normal humans.
Doubt and suspicion, irrational rage and hatred...
They sow the seeds of catastrophe in this world.
Many inexplicable suicides and murders that occur are caused by a witch's curse.
It's a formless evil that eats away at humans from the inside.
If they're so dangerous, then how come no one knows about them?
Because witches hide within barriers
and never show themselves to people.
The labyrinth-like area you wandered into before was one.
They're pretty dangerous, actually.
Those who are swallowed up by the barriers don't usually live to tell the tale.
Mami, are you really fighting something that dangerous?
Yes.
Sometimes my life is in danger too.
That's why I think you two should weigh your options carefully.
Now that you've been chosen by Kyubey,
you can have any wish granted.
However, doing so could lead to your death.
That's a tough decision.
To help you make up your minds,
why don't you come along
with me on a witch hunt?
Huh?
That way you can see what
it's like to fight a witch.
And afterwards, you should take the time and think about
whether having your wish
come true is worth your life.
Good morning!
Good morning.
Good mor—
Good morning, Sayaka.
Is something wrong, Sayaka?
So we're really the only ones who can see him?
Looks like it.
Um...
Don't worry about it.
Let's go.
Looks like we can also talk to each other telepathically.
Wait, so we already have magical powers?!
No, no. I'm just using myself
to relay your thoughts.
It's pretty convenient though, isn't it?
It feels a bit strange.
Hey, what's going on with you two?
You keep staring into each other's eyes.
N-No, we've been... Um...
No, don't say it!
Are you two already close enough to
communicate through your eyes alone?!
I can't believe you've become so close
to each other after just one day.
What on Earth happened yesterday?
No, uh... you've got it all wrong.
A lot did happen last night, though.
You can't! You're both girls!
It's a love that can never be!
You forgot your bag!
Hitomi's acting a bit like you today.
What's that supposed to mean?!
Is it okay for you to come with us to school like nothing's happened?
Why wouldn't it be?
I told you that the girl from yesterday transferred into this class, right?
Wasn't she trying to kill you?
I actually think the school
is the safest place for me.
Mami's here too.
Mami's a third-year, so her
class is kind of far from here.
Don't worry.
I can hear everything you're saying.
Even at this distance, we can still communicate with her.
U-Uh... good morning.
I'll keep a close eye on you all, so don't worry.
Besides, I'm pretty sure she wouldn't attack any of you in public.
I hope you're right.
Damn. Speak of the devil.
So is that transfer student also an, uh...
what was it? Magical girl?
Just like you, Mami?
Yes, she is.
She seems quite powerful too.
Wouldn't that make her one of the good guys fighting evil witches?
Why did she suddenly attack Madoka, then?
She was after me.
I imagine she was trying to stop
the creation of new magical girls.
Huh?
Why? Wouldn't it be better to have
more people fighting the same enemy?
That's not necessarily the case.
It's actually more common for us to compete with each other.
Really? Why?
There are rewards for eliminating a witch.
So, in some cases, it turns into a contest,
and magical girls may even fight over them.
So basically, she predicted that
Kyubey would try to talk to Madoka,
and that's why she's been pestering
Madoka since this morning?
That's most likely the case.
Don't worry, Madoka.
If she tries to do anything,
I'll punch her lights out!
We've even got Mami here.
That's right.
Miki's ability to protect you aside,
I'm with you, so everything will be fine.
Don't worry.
Don't put me aside!
So, as we've learned thus far,
a phrase is in the "active voice" when the subject—
a person or thing—performs the action.
In contrast, a phrase is in the "passive voice" when the subject receives the action.
Passive voice is formed by an auxiliary verb with the participle of a transitive verb.
For instance, if I were to say, "He likes me,"
or "kare wa watashi no koto ga suki"—
Here you go.
Hey, Madoka.
Have you come up with a wish yet?
Nope. What about you?
Me neither.
I kind of thought a whole bunch
of things would pop into my mind...
I mean, there are a bunch of
things I want to have and do,
but when risking our lives
is the catch... you know?
I don't think anything I
want is worth that risk.
Yeah.
That's surprising.
Most girls answer immediately.
I guess we're just idiots.
Huh? You really think so?
Yep. Blissfully ignorant idiots.
Having a wish you'd trade your life for
shouldn't be all that uncommon.
I'm sure a lot of people in
the world have a wish like that.
So if we can't think of anything,
then it must mean we haven't
faced much misfortune.
Living such a sheltered life
has made us ignorant.
But why us... of all people?
Don't you think it's unfair?
I'm sure there are other people who'd
give anything for a chance like this.
Sayaka...
Don't worry.
Picking up where you left off yesterday?
No, that's not my intention.
I had hoped to settle things before he made contact with Kaname Madoka,
but it's too late for that now.
So what will you do?
Have you two decided to
become magical girls as well?
I...
That's none of your business!
Do you remember what I told you yesterday?
Yeah...
That's fine, then.
I pray that my warning won't fall on deaf ears.
Ho... Homura!
What... wish did you make
to become a magical girl?
Sorry, Hitomi.
We have a few things to do today.
Oh, something secret?
We...
I'm so jealous!
No one can come between
you two anymore, can they?
Uh, you're really misunderstanding us...
Akemi, wanna come to a café with us?
I have something I need to
take care of again today.
I'm sorry.
Okay, let's begin our first lesson on the magical girl experience.
Are you two ready?
I'm not sure if it'll help, but I brought this!
I thought it'd be better than nothing.
Well, it's good to see you're
mentally prepared to fight.
Madoka, did you bring anything?
Huh? Oh, I have this...
Wow...
I-I figured I might as well
think about the costume.
You're enthusiastic, that's for sure.
That's great.
I can't top that.
It's reacting to the remnants of the magic used by that witch we faced yesterday.
Searching for witches basically involves a lot of walking.
All you do is follow the Soul Gem as it traces the witch's presence.
That's pretty lame.
The light hasn't changed at all.
It's been a whole day since it escaped.
There's very little left to track.
What if you had gone after it yesterday?
I might have been able to defeat it,
but it wasn't worth leaving you two behind.
I'm sorry.
It's fine.
Mami's one of the good guys!
On the other hand, that transfer
student really gets on my nerves!
I wonder if she's really that bad.
Hey, Mami. Do you have any idea of where the witch might be?
Witches' curses tend to cause traffic accidents and assaults.
So I prioritize major highways and entertainment districts where accidents and brawls are likely,
as well as desolate places
that are perfect for suicides.
The worst case scenario is when they haunt places like hospitals.
It's not a pretty sight when they drain
the life out of those in a weakened state.
It's reacting to some very powerful magic.
It must be close.
It has to be here!
Mami, look!
A witch's kiss.
I knew it.
Is she...
It's okay.
She's just unconscious.
Let's go.
You're not getting away today!
Wow.
It's nothing special, but at the very least it'll help protect you.
Make sure you stay by my side, okay?
Okay!
Stay away! Stay away!
So, are you two scared?
Th-This is nothing!
I'm scared, but...
Keep it up!
We're almost at the barrier's core!
Look, that's a witch.
Disgusting...
Are you going to fight that?
It's okay.
I won't lose.
Stay back.
Mami!
Don't worry.
I can't just embarrass myself in front of my future protégés.
Close, but no cigar.
Tiro Finale!
She won?
Wow.
This is a Grief Seed.
It's a witch's egg.
E-Egg?
If you're lucky, sometimes
a witch will have one.
Don't worry.
It's safe in that form.
Actually, it's extremely useful.
My Soul Gem is a bit darker
than it was last night, right?
Oh. Yeah, it is.
However, by using a Grief Seed...
Take a look.
It's all clean.
See?
Now the magic I've depleted
has been replenished.
This is one of the rewards I mentioned earlier.
You should be able to use it one more time.
You can have it,
Akemi Homura.
It's her.
Or do you not like to share?
It was your prey.
You should keep it for yourself.
I see. So that's your answer.
That antisocial bitch!
I wish we could all just get along.
If only everyone felt that same way.
Where am I?
Wait, what was I doing?
Wh-Why was I...
Why did I do that?
It's okay. Everything's okay now.
You were just having a bad dream.
Looks like our hero saved the day.
Yeah.
It's too hard for me to come up
with a wish on such short notice,
but the sight of Mami pouring her
heart into saving others was really amazing.
If someone like me can really help other people,
I think that'd be really nice.
I waved my hand, saying, "I'll see you next time"
I forced a smile, then I was lonely...
Traffic lights at the intersection...
The distant sound of a car honking...
The voices of strangers laughing
Today, I walk alone
Even though I'm used to the city,
I feel just a little smaller
than my usual self
I wave my hand, saying, "I'll see you next time"
I made a smile, then I was lonely...
Even though I want to talk even more with you...
Saying, "I'll see you next time,"
Lying about seeing each other again
I say, with my usual smile,
"See you tomorrow."
Illustrated by  Hikawa Hekiru
I'm just acting cool,
but I have no one to talk
with when I'm scared or sad...
I'm forced to cry all alone.
Being a magical girl
really isn't that great.
I'm not scared of anything anymore.
I'm not scared of anything anymore
Episode 3